<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="datasetPresenters.xslt"?>
<!DOCTYPE datasetPresenters SYSTEM "datasetPresenters.dtd">
<datasetPresenters>

<!--
  <datasetPresenter name=""
                    projectName="TriTrypDB"
                    buildNumberIntroduced="18"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[                ]]> </displayName>
    <summary><![CDATA[                ]]>  </summary>
    <description><![CDATA[                ]]>  </description>
    <primaryContactId></primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>  
    </datasetPresenter>
  -->


  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Vinayak_FosmidEnds_clonedInsertEnds_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    buildNumberIntroduced="18"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned End-Sequenced Fosmids]]> </displayName>
    <summary><![CDATA[<i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> RH sequence from fosmid ends mapped against <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 ]]>  </summary>
    <description><![CDATA[
    The <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> RH fosmid library was constructed by Sumiti Vinayak in the copy control vector pCC2FOS. 
    Fosmid ends were sequenced commercially (Sanger method) using vector specific primers. Resulting sequences were 
    aligned to the <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 genome using BLAST. 
     <br><br> 
    
    Funds for sequencing were provided by 
    Boris Striepen (University of Georgia, Athens, GA, USA), Markus Meissner (University of Glasgow, Scotland) 
    and Michael White (University of South Florida, Tampa, FL, USA). 
                   ]]>  </description>
    <caveat> Note that fosmid inserts typically are not larger than ~45,000 bp (mean size ~34,000 bp), 
    very large inserts depicted in gbrowse may reflect mismatched end sequences.</caveat>
    <primaryContactId>boris.striepen</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>markus.meissner</contactId>
    <contactId>sumiti.vinayak</contactId>
    <contactId>michael.white</contactId>
    <link>
      <text>pCC2FOS vector</text>
      <url>http://www.epibio.com/products/genomic-library-construction-kits-gene-pcr-cloning-kits/cloning-genomic/copycontrol-fosmid-library-production-kit?details</url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>  
 </datasetPresenter>


  <datasetPresenter name="_massSpec_Boothroyd_Elias_Moritz_Phosphoproteome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    datasetNamePattern="%_massSpec_Boothroyd_Elias_Moritz_Phosphoproteome_RSRC">
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Tachyzoite phosphoproteome from purified parasite or infected host cell (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
Protein samples were prepared from infected host cells or from purified T gondii RH strain tachyzoites. Phosphorylated and non-phosphorylated peptides were separated by SCX chromotography, enriched by IMAC chromotography, and analyzed by LC-MS/MS. To discover the peptide composition of samples, mass spec data was searched against TgME49 and TgGT1 peptide databases. 
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
Sample collection and mass-spectrometry were performed by Moritz Treeck and John Sanders of the Boothroyd and Elias labs at Stanford University, respectively.  See further explanation in Treeck <i>et. al.</i>, 2011, Cell Host & Microbe, in press.
<br><br>
<b>Intracellular RH tachyzoite samples:</b><br>
Tachyzoites (RH strain) were used to infect HFF (human foreskin fibroblasts) for 28h. Extracellular parasites were washed off and the parasite-infected host cells lysed and the entire sample used for phosphopeptide enrichment and mass-spectrometry. 
<br><br>
<b>Purified RH tachyzoite samples:</b><br>
Purified tachyzoite samples (RH strain) were prepared by infection of HFFs with RH parasites for 28h. To remove host cell material and parasite proteins present within the host cell or parasitophorous vacuole, the infected cultures were syringe-lysed and the released parasites were then purified by gel chromatography as described in Dunn <i>et. al.</i>, 2008 (Infection & Immunity). All parasite samples were lysed in 8m urea lysis buffer, followed by trypsin digestion, strong-cation-exchange (SCX) chromatography and IMAC phosphopeptide enrichment (Villen and Gygi, 2008). Samples enriched for phosphopeptides and the flow through (containing predominantly non-phosphorylated peptides) were analyzed in duplicate via LC-MS/MS and the resulting spectra were searched against appropriate parasite protein sequence databases concatenated with reversed decoy versions of these sequences using the SEQUEST algorithm (Eng et al., 1994). Phosphorylation sites were localized using the AScore algorithm (Beausoleil et al., 2006) and the dataset was filtered using the target-decoy strategy (Elias and Gygi 2007, 2010) for peptide and phosphorylation site-FDRs <1% and a protein FDR <3%.
This bulk FDR prediction estimates that fewer than 1% of the identifications are incorrect. Given that a phosphopeptide was correctly identified, its phosphorylation sites are necessarily present, but the site’s localization to a specific amino acid can be ambiguous.  As a result, the Ascore algorithm was used to help localize phosphorylation sites to a specific residue. This algorithm calculates the relative likelihood that the indicated amino acid is phosphorylated versus the next-most likely residue on the peptide. An Ascore >19 indicates a >99% likelihood that the indicated phosphorylation site is correctly assigned; an Ascore >13-represents a 95% likelihood; and an Ascore >10 corresponds with a >90% likelihood. As a rule of thumb, a phosphorylation site with many spectral counts, indicating many observations, tend to be more abundant than those with fewer spectral counts.  While it is true that most incorrect identifications have few spectral counts, it is not necessarily the case that phosphorylation sites with few spectral counts are incorrect.  
Further scores to evaluate each individual site and peptide can be found in the supplementary data Table S1 and S2 in Treeck <i>et. al.</i>, 2011, Cell Host & Microbe, in press. 
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.boothroyd</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>22018241</pubmedId>
	<templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev">T.g.</prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">true</prop>
	</templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  
  <datasetPresenter name="ncanLIV_Gregory_Brian_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[mRNA RNA-Seq Tachyzoites]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[
         <i>N. caninum</i>  mRNA Illumina sequences (RNA-Seq)   
        ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[Transcript expression was assayed in <i>N. caninum</i> tachyzoites.  The experiment was conducted as follows:<br><br>
<i>N. caninum</i> tachyzoites were propagated on Vero cells before being used to infect Human Foreskin Fibroblasts (HFFs). T25 flasks containing confluent monolayers of HFFs were infected with approximately 10E^7 tachyzoites.<br><br>
 Total RNA samples were extracted from multiple sources. <i>N. caninum</i> tachyzoite total RNA was extracted post infection (36hpi for Nc1). <br><br>
At several timepoints post-infection (all prior to observable host cell lysis) media was removed, cell monolayers were scraped in 700ul of Qiazol, and RNA was isolated from the cell lysates using the Qiagen miRNEasy mini kit according to manufacturer's instructions.  6 flasks (biological replicates) were collected per strain and per timepoint, and were checked for RNA quality using a BioAnalyzer (Agilent). Biological replicates were pooled and total and polyA+ selected RNA was used to construct strand specific small non-coding or mRNA libraries respectively, that were sequenced on Illumina Hi-Seq 2000 and Genome Analyzer machines.   ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>brian.d.gregory</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>david.s.roos</contactId>
    <contactId>maria.alejandra.diaz-miranda</contactId>
    <contactId>daniel.beiting</contactId>
    <contactId>qi.zheng</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.RNASeqGregoryVEG">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_Gregory_VEG_mRNA_rnaSeq_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Gregory::TgVegRnaSeqTS</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Time point in hours]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[Transcript levels of reads per kilobase of exon model per million mapped reads (RPKM).  Stacked bars indicate unique and non-uniquely mapped sequences.  Non-Unique sequences are plotted to indicate the maximum expression potential of this gene.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rpkm_sense,percentile_sense,rpkm_antisense,percentile_antisense</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">780</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Moreno_preprocessed_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Tachyzoite subcellular fractions</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            Proteomics data provided by Silvia Moreno's lab from the University of Georgia, Athens, GA. Two data sets (samples A and G) were graciously provided pre-publication. Samples were prepared from RH parasites by Silvia Moreno's laboratory at the University of Georgia, Athens, GA and analyzed by James Thompson and  John  Yates, III  at The Scripps Research Institute, La Jolla, CA.<br>
This data was graciously provided to ToxoDB pre-publication by Silvia Moreno (smoreno@cb.uga.edu).
          
          ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>silvia.moreno</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_NuclearNonCoding_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Expression-NuclearNonCoding]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_IbIntron_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Expresssion-IbIntron]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_dbxref_protein2EinsteinAntibodies_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Links to Antibodies from Albert Einstein College of Medicine]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
                Antibodies against <i>T. gondii</i> epitopes generated by the <a href="http://toro.aecom.yu.edu/biodefense/"TARGET="_blank">Albert Einstein Biodefense Proteomics Research Center</a>.<br>
Antibodies may be obatined for free from the Biodefense and Emerging Infections Research Resources Repository.
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>biodefense.proteomics.research.center</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.LinksMR4"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Wastling-MudPIT_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[MudPIT Soluble Fraction]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
            MudPIT soluble fraction proteomics data provided by Jonathan Wastling lab
          
          ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            MudPIT soluble fraction proteomics data provided by Jonathan Wastling lab
          
          ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>jonathan.m.wastling</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_SNP_Lindstrom_454_gff_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned SNPs:  TgCkUg2 Strain]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
         
   Whole genome sequence of the natural recombinant <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> strain TgCkUg2 was provided by Irene Lindstrom Bontell and Judith E Smith, Institute of Integrative and Comparative Biology, Clarendon Way, University of Leeds, Leeds, LS2 9JT, UK. 
          
     ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
   Whole genome sequence of the natural recombinant <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> strain TgCkUg2 was provided by Irene Lindstrom Bontell and Judith E Smith, Institute of Integrative and Comparative Biology, Clarendon Way, University of Leeds, Leeds, LS2 9JT, UK. 
          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>irene.lindstrom</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>19457243</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.SNPs"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_SNP_Sibley_Tg10x_31_gff_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned Genetic Markers]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
   Genetic Markers for T. gondii provided by  L. David Sibley (Washington University in St. Louis). Contact: L. David Sibley sibley&#64;borcim&#46;wustl&#46;edu
            
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   Genetic Markers for T. gondii provided by  L. David Sibley (Washington University in St. Louis). Contact: L. David Sibley sibley&#64;borcim&#46;wustl&#46;edu
            
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.sibley</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>15911631</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.SNPs"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonFOU_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> FOU strain genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> FOU strain genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
<p>Data Usage Policy</p>
<p>NIAID is committed to rapid, pre-publication release of genomic data and recognizes that clinical data and other metadata associated with the genomic data are valuable research resources.  For these reasons, NIAID endorses rapid release of all genome data sets.  To comply with this policy, the whole genome sequences of T. gondii strains are being submitted to NCBI and included here in ToxoDB prior to complete annotation.  Once annotation is complete and submitted to GenBank, the entries for these new genomes will be updated in ToxoDB.  The users of any released data are expected to act responsibly to recognize the scientific contribution of the data producers by following normal standards of scientific etiquette and fair use of unpublished data.  In particular, we ask that users not perform genome wide comparisons/analyses of the sequence/open reading frames/genes of the data sets deposited here without first contacting the organizing committee.  We welcome your input in this process, but would also like to coordinate community efforts to with the goal of producing a collective report for publication.  If you have an idea for analyses that would be useful, please contact one of us to coordinate your contribution to the community effort.</p><br>
<p>Brian Brunk, Hernan Lorenzi, David Roos & David Sibley, on behalf of the Toxoplasma genome consortium, representing the white paper committee, the JCVI genome sequencing center, and the ToxoDB team.</p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_oldAnnotation_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Old Annotation for T. gondii ME49 (typeII)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
   Annotation of the <i>T. gondii</i> type II ME49 chromosomes by the Toxoplasma Genome Consortium.  For further information contact Ian Paulsen (The Institute for Genomic Research)  ipaulsen&#64;tigr&#46;org, or David Roos (University of Pennsylvania) droos&#64;sas&#46;upenn&#46;edu.
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   Annotation of the <i>T. gondii</i> type II ME49 chromosomes by the Toxoplasma Genome Consortium.  For further information contact Ian Paulsen (The Institute for Genomic Research)  ipaulsen&#64;tigr&#46;org, or David Roos (University of Pennsylvania) droos&#64;sas&#46;upenn&#46;edu.
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>ian.paulsen</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_dbxref_protein2Pathways_Feng_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Metabolic Pathway Reconstruction]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
   Metabolic Pathway Reconstruction for <i>T. gondii</i> gene identifiers, provided on 2006-04-06 by Feng Chen and David Roos (University of Pennsylvania). Contact: David Roos droos&#64;sas&#46;upenn&#46;edu
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   Metabolic Pathway Reconstruction for <i>T. gondii</i> gene identifiers, provided on 2006-04-06 by Feng Chen and David Roos (University of Pennsylvania). Contact: David Roos droos&#64;sas&#46;upenn&#46;edu
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>feng.chen</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.PathwayRoos"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Sullivan_GSE22100_GCN5-A_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Differential Expression Profiling GCN5-A mutant]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 

Differential experssion of TgGCN5-A null mutant under Alkaline growth conditions compared to wild type.
<br/><br/>


          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 

Differential experssion of TgGCN5-A null mutant under Alkaline growth conditions compared to wild type.
<br/><br/>

Disruption of the gene encoding for TgGCN5-A in type I RH strain did not produce a severe phenotype 
under normal culture conditions, but here we show that the TgGCN5-A null mutant is deficient in responding to alkaline pH,
a common stress used to induce bradyzoite differentiation in vitro. We performed a genome- wide analysis of the Toxoplasma 
transcriptional response to alkaline pH stress, finding that parasites deleted for TgGCN5-A fail to up-regulate 74% of the 
stress response genes that are induced 2-fold or more in wild-type. Using chromatin immunoprecipitation, we verify an enrichment
of TgGCN5-A at the upstream regions of genes activated by alkaline pH exposure. The TgGCN5-A knockout is also incapable of 
up-regulating key marker genes expressed during development of the latent cyst form, and is impaired in its ability to recover 
from alkaline stress. Complementation of the TgGCN5-A knockout restores the expression of these stress-induced genes and reverses 
the stress recovery defect.
Click <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/query/acc.cgi?acc=GSE22100"> here for link to GEO</a>
<br/><br/>
Authors: Arunasalam Naguleswaran, Eliana V. Elias, Jeanette McClintick, Howard J. Edenberg, William J. Sullivan Jr
            

          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>william.sullivan</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>21179246</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarraySullivanGCN5A">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Sullivan_GSE22100_GCN5-A_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Sullivan::GCN5A</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[There are 4 samples divided based on two criteria            1. Strain Type                a. Wild Type: unmodified ME49 strain               b. GCN5-A Knockout: ME49 with GCN5-A gene deletion            2. Growth Conditions                a. unstressed: samples were grown in standard culture medium               b. stressed: samples were grown in alkaline culture medium]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[RMA Normalized Values (log base 2 generated with RMAExpress v1.0.3) or expression percentile value.The RMA values in log2 scale.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">160</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_sageTag_White5primeSageTags_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[5-prime SAGE Tags]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
   5-prime SAGE tags for <i>T. gondii</i> provided on 2005-04-26, by Aaron Mackey and Michael Behnke, Michael White (Montana State University). Contact: Michael White <tt>uvsmw&#64;montana&#46;edu</tt>
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   5-prime SAGE tags for <i>T. gondii</i> provided on 2005-04-26, by Aaron Mackey and Michael Behnke, Michael White (Montana State University). Contact: Michael White <tt>uvsmw&#64;montana&#46;edu</tt>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>michael.w.white</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>16324218</pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonGT1_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence and Annotation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
            Toxoplasma gondii GT1 sequence and  annotation from  Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).

    
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            Toxoplasma gondii GT1 sequence and  annotation from  Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).

    
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonVEG_oldContigs_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence and Annotation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
 Toxoplasma gondii VEG sequence and annotation from Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
 Toxoplasma gondii VEG sequence and annotation from Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Roos-Tz-Bz_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Bradyzoite Differentiation (Multiple 6-hr time points and Extended time series)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
         
Expression profiles of T. gondii time series (Multiple 6-hr time points and Extended time series).
<br> This data was graciously provided to ToxoDB pre-publication by Paul Davis, Florence Dzierszinski and David Roos.
          
     ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
Expression profiles of T. gondii time series (Multiple 6-hr time points and Extended time series).
<br> This data was graciously provided to ToxoDB pre-publication by Paul Davis, Florence Dzierszinski and David Roos.
          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>paul.h.davis</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayRoosBrady"> 
<prop name="graphModule">Roos::TzBz</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">roos_rma,roos_percentile,dzierszinski_rma,dzierszinski_percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">80</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  
  <!--  
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Boothroyd_Elias_Moritz_Phosphoproteome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Purified T. gondii total proteome provided by Moritz and Boothroyd]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            Phosphoproteome from Toxoplasma Tachizoites within- and purified from host-cells. This is from Moritz Treeck in John Boothroyd's lab. For the Oocyst data: Oocyst Proteomics data from John Boothroyd (DBP material) - Fritz HM, *Bowyer PW, Bogyo MS, Conrad PA, Boothroyd JC. Proteomic characterization of mature Toxoplasma gondii oocysts: identification of candidate wall and sporozoite components
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.boothroyd</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>		
	<templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">true</prop>
	</templateInjector>
	
  </datasetPresenter>
-->

  

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Wastling-rhoptry_preprocessed_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Tachyzoite Rhoptry proteome (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
The purified rhoptry fraction from T. gondii RH strain tachyzoites was analyzed by 1DE, LC-MS/MS.             

          
          ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>jonathan.m.wastling</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>16002398</pubmedId>
	<templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>	
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Reid_tachy_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Tachyzoite mRNA-Seqs ]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
          
Transcriptome analysis of T. gondii VEG and N. caninum Liverpool tachyzoites using RNAseq RNA sequencing data
          
           ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
          
Transcriptome analysis of T. gondii VEG and N. caninum Liverpool tachyzoites using RNAseq RNA sequencing data
          
           ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>adam.reid</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>22457617</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.RNASeqReidDay3">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_Reid_tachy_rnaSeq_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Reid::TgVEGRnaSeq</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[T. gondii ME49 Day 3 and Day4 Tachyzoite Form]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[Transcript levels of fragments per kilobase of exon model per million mapped reads (FPKM).  Stacked bars indicate unique and non-uniquely mapped sequences.  Non-Unique sequences are plotted to indicate the maximum expression potential of this gene.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">fpkm,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">600</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonVEG_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence and Annotation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
            Toxoplasma gondii VEG sequence and annotation from Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
             
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            Toxoplasma gondii VEG sequence and annotation from Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
             
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.AnnotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>

  <!-- TODO:  Perhaps move these to global?? -->
  <datasetPresenter name="etenHoughton_dbxref_ApiLoc_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    override="_dbxref_ApiLoc_RSRC"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[ApiLoc and EupathDb links]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ApiLoc and EupathDb links]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>stuart.ralph</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="ncanLIV_dbxref_ApiLoc_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    override="_dbxref_ApiLoc_RSRC"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[ApiLoc and EupathDb links]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ApiLoc and EupathDb links]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>stuart.ralph</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_dbxref_ApiLoc_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    override="_dbxref_ApiLoc_RSRC"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[ApiLoc and EupathDb links]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ApiLoc and EupathDb links]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>stuart.ralph</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <!-- end apiloc -->


  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_isolates_ChunleiSu_RFLP_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[RFLP sequences]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
   <i>T. gondii</i> RFLP sequences (Chunlei Su lab)
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   <i>T. gondii</i> RFLP sequences (Chunlei Su lab)
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>chunlei.su</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.IsolatesSuRFLP"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_oldTigr_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Gene Predictions from TigrScan]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
  <a target='new' href="http://cbcb.umd.edu/software/pirate/">TigrScan</a>
  was trained for <i>T. gondii</i> by TIGR; the parameters are
  available <a target='new'  href="http://cbcb.umd.edu/software/pirate/tigrscan-toxoplasma.tar.gz">here</a>. Gene predictions for <i>T. gondii</i> produced by TigrScan, provided by Aaron Mackey, David Roos  (University of Pennsylvania).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Roos-Tz_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Expression profiling of the 3 archetypal T. gondii lineages]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
         
Expression profiling of two strains from each of the 3 archetypal <i>T. gondii</i> lineages.  This data was graciously provided to ToxoDB pre-publication by Paul Davis and David Roos.

          
     ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
Expression profiling of two strains from each of the 3 archetypal <i>T. gondii</i> lineages was generated as per the following experiment:<br>
At least three T25 flasks containing confluent monolayers of human foreskin fibroblasts grown in D10 media were infected with approximately 1x10<sup>7</sup> <i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoite parasites per strain.  After 6hrs, the media was replaced with fresh D10.  Approximately 40hr post-infection (and prior to observable host cell lysis), media was removed and flasks were washed once with 1x cold PBS.  Cell monolayers were scraped in 5ml 1x cold PBS, and centrifuged for 12min, 750g at 4C.  Supernatant was removed, and RNA was isolated from the cell pellets using Qiagen RNEasy kit according to manufacturer's instructions.<br>
Strains utilized:<br>
Type I:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;RH and GT1<br>
Type II:&nbsp;&nbsp;Pru and ME49<br>
Type III:&nbsp;CTG and VEG<br>
This data was graciously provided to ToxoDB pre-publication by Paul Davis and David Roos.

          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayRoosTzLineages">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Roos-Tz_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Roos::ToxoLineages::Ver1</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Strain]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[RMA Normalized Values (log base 2 generated with RMAExpress v1.0.3)]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">0</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Boothroyd_Bowyer_oocyst_sporozoite_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Oocyst proteome (M4 type II)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
Mature "day 10" Toxoplasma gondii oocysts of the Type II M4 strain were fractionated into walls (bleach treated, and untreated) and sporocysts/sporozoites. Protein preparations were analyzed by 1DE, LC-MS/MS.         
       ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
        <br/><br/>
        Heather M. Fritz*, Paul W. Bowyer*, Matthew Bogyo, Patricia A. Conrad, John C. Boothroyd
        *these authors contributed equally to this work
        <br/><br/> 


        Mature "day 10" Toxoplasma gondii oocysts of the Type II M4 strain were used for proteomic characterization of the wall and sporocyst/sporozoite fractions of the oocyst by mass spectrometry.  Two experiments using 100 million oocysts each were performed. For each experiment oocysts were fractionated into wall and sporocyst/sporozoite components. In the second experiment, the 100 million oocysts were first divided into bleach-treated and not-treated fractions.  Bleach treatment was used to remove the outer layer of the bilayered oocyst wall before fractionation. Therefore, comparison of the bleach-treated to not-treated walls allowed us to interrogate the inner versus outer wall location of identified proteins in the wall fraction. Data from the bleach-treated and not-treated sporocyst fractions in experiment two were pooled, as bleach treatment of the intact oocysts should not affect the sporocysts within.  

        <br/><br/>
        Peptide identifications for the following oocyst fractions are provided:

        <br/><br/>
        1.  Oocyst walls (bleach-treated)
        <br/>
        2.  Oocyst walls (not-treated)
        <br/>
        3.  Sporocysts/Sporozoites
<br/><br/>
<b>Sample preparation:</b>
<br/><br/>
Oocyst harvest, bleach treatment and fractionation into walls and sporocysts/sporozoites 
Unsporulated oocysts were harvested from the feces of infected kittens and sporulated for 10 days.  Sporulated oocysts were then purified using a CsCl gradient separation. Half of the oocysts in the second experiment were treated with bleach to remove the outer layer of the oocyst wall.  For each sample, oocysts were separated into walls and sporocysts using an iodixanol (Optiprep, SIGMA) gradient separation. 

<br/><br/>
Protein Preparation and Mass Spectrometry (MS) 
<br/><br/>
Oocyst fractions were separated by 1-D SDS-PAGE on a 7 cm long gel.  The entire length of each sample lane was cut into 14, 0.5 cm, slices.  Gel slices were subjected to in-gel digestion with trypsin before analysis on an LTQ ion trap mass spectrometer (ThermoFisher).
<br/><br/>
LC-MS/MS 
<br/><br/>
Peptides were separated on a Basic Picofrit C18 capillary column coupled to an Eksigent nanoLC-2D pump before analysis on an LTQ ion trap.  Peptides were eluted with an acetonitrile gradient from 0 to 60% in a 0.1% solution of formic acid over 2hr. Dynamic exclusion was enabled for 180 sec.  
<br/><br/>
Data Analysis 
<br/><br/>
Searches were performed against a custom concatenated target-decoy database containing the annotated proteins based on the T. gondii ME49 release 5 sequences.  Peptides in the +1, +2 and +3 charge-states were required to have minimum XCorr values of 1.8, 2.5 and 3.5, respectively.  The minimum requirement for deltaCN was 0.08. Both tryptic and semi-tryptic peptides are shown.  
        
       ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.boothroyd</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>22279555</pubmedId>
	<templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>	
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Wastling_SDSPage_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Tachyzoite total proteome (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
          Total protein from T gondii (RH strain) tachyzoites (harvested 3-4 days post-infection) was analyzed by 1DE, LC-MS/MS and MudPIT analysis. Purified tachyzoites were either solubilized directly in SDS sample buffer or prepared as Tris-soluble and Tris insoluble fractions prior to 1DE, LC-MS/MS. MudPit analysis was performed on Tris-soluble and Tris-insoluble fractions. 
          ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            Proteomics data includes the following samples:<br><br>
1-D SDS PAGE Total Fraction<br>
1-D SDS PAGE Soluble Fraction<br>
1-D SDS PAGE Insoluble Fraction<br>
MudPIT Soluble Fraction<br>
MudPIT Insoluble Fraction
          
          ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>jonathan.m.wastling</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>18644147</pubmedId>
	<templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>	
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_chipChipExper_Einstein_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Chromatin Immunoprecipitation Microarray - Active Transcriptome]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            
       Chromatin Immunoprecipitation chip data identifying regions of active transcription. Peak calls were made by the data provider.  
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
       Chromatin Immunoprecipitation chip data identifying regions of active transcription. Peak calls were made by the data provider.  
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>kami.kim</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.ChIPChip"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_Antisense_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Expresssion-Antisense]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Carruthers_GSE20480_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Transcript Profiling Infection]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
             Here we show that host cell transmission of the obligate intracellular parasite Toxoplasma gondii is closely tied to specific cell cycle distributions, with egress and reinvasion occurring most proficiently by parasites in the G1 phase. We also reveal that Toxoplasma undergoes marked changes in mRNA expression when transitioning from the extracellular environment to its intracellular niche. These mRNA level changes reflect a modal switch from expression of proteins involved in invasion, motility and signal transduction in extracellular parasites to expression of metabolic and DNA replication proteins in intracellular parasites.

Three sample types were harvested: extracellular, intracellular 0hr, intracellular 2hr. 2 replicates each. Expression for >80% of the regulated genes exhibits a steady downregulation during invasion. Click <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/query/acc.cgi?acc=GSE20480"> here for link to GEO</a>
<br/><br/>
Authors: Rajshekhar Y. Gaji, Michael S. Behnke, Margaret M. Lehmann, Michael W. White, Vern B. Carruthers
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>vern.b.carruthers</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>21166903</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayCarruthersInvasion">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Carruthers_GSE20480_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Carruthers::IntraExtraDiff</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Sample Type             1. Extracellular: Harvested from outside the cell, pre-invasion             2. Intracellular_0hr: Harvested from inside the cell, shortly after invasion             3. Intracellular_2hr: Harvested from inside the cell, 2 hours after invasion]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[RMA Normalized Values (log base 2 generated with RMAExpress v1.0.3) or expression percentile value.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">40</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonGT1_oldJCVI_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence and Annotation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
 Toxoplasma gondii GT1 sequence and annotation from Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonGT1_gb_GOAssociations_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    override="_GOAssociations_RSRC"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Protein GO Associations]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    <displayCategory>Genomes and Annotation</displayCategory>
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   <i>T. gondii</i> GT1 Gene Ontology  associations produced by Lis Caler's group at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_oldContigs_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence and Annotation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
Toxoplasma gondii ME49 sequence and annotation from Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_SNP_Stanford_Tg10x_31_gff_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned SNPs:  EST Bases]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   EST-based SNP data for T. gondii (ME49) provided by Jon Boyle and John Boothroyd (Stanford University). Contact: John Boothroyd jboothr&#64;stanford&#46;edu
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.boothroyd</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>16801557</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.SNPs"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonTgCATBr9_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> TgCATBr9 strain genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the  <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
<p>Data Usage Policy</p>
<p>NIAID is committed to rapid, pre-publication release of genomic data and recognizes that clinical data and other metadata associated with the genomic data are valuable research resources.  For these reasons, NIAID endorses rapid release of all genome data sets.  To comply with this policy, the whole genome sequences of T. gondii strains are being submitted to NCBI and included here in ToxoDB prior to complete annotation.  Once annotation is complete and submitted to GenBank, the entries for these new genomes will be updated in ToxoDB.  The users of any released data are expected to act responsibly to recognize the scientific contribution of the data producers by following normal standards of scientific etiquette and fair use of unpublished data.  In particular, we ask that users not perform genome wide comparisons/analyses of the sequence/open reading frames/genes of the data sets deposited here without first contacting the organizing committee.  We welcome your input in this process, but would also like to coordinate community efforts to with the goal of producing a collective report for publication.  If you have an idea for analyses that would be useful, please contact one of us to coordinate your contribution to the community effort.</p><br>
<p>Brian Brunk, Hernan Lorenzi, David Roos & David Sibley, on behalf of the Toxoplasma genome consortium, representing the white paper committee, the JCVI genome sequencing center, and the ToxoDB team.</p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Gregory_ME49_ncRNA_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[ncRNA RNA-Seqs Tachyzoites]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[
         <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 ncRNA Illumina sequences aligned to the ME49 Genome   
       ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[Transcript expression was assayed in <i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoites.  The experiment was conducted as follows:<br><br>
<i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoites were propagated on Vero cells before being used to infect Human Foreskin Fibroblasts (HFFs). T25 flasks containing confluent monolayers of HFFs were infected with approximately 10E^7 tachyzoites.<br><br>
 Total RNA samples were extracted from multiple sources. <i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoite total RNA was extracted at several times post infection (24hpi for RH; 33hpi for ME49, 44hpi for VEG and 36hpi for Nc1). <br><br>
At several timepoints post-infection (all prior to observable host cell lysis) media was removed, cell monolayers were scraped in 700ul of Qiazol, and RNA was isolated from the cell lysates using the Qiagen miRNEasy mini kit according to manufacturer's instructions.  6 flasks (biological replicates) were collected per strain and per timepoint, and were checked for RNA quality using a BioAnalyzer (Agilent). Biological replicates were pooled and total and polyA+ selected RNA was used to construct strand specific small non-coding or mRNA libraries respectively, that were sequenced on Illumina Hi-Seq 2000 and Genome Analyzer machines.   ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>brian.d.gregory</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>david.s.roos</contactId>
    <contactId>maria.alejandra.diaz-miranda</contactId>
    <contactId>daniel.beiting</contactId>
    <contactId>qi.zheng</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonVAND_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> VAND strain genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
<p>Data Usage Policy</p>
<p>NIAID is committed to rapid, pre-publication release of genomic data and recognizes that clinical data and other metadata associated with the genomic data are valuable research resources.  For these reasons, NIAID endorses rapid release of all genome data sets.  To comply with this policy, the whole genome sequences of T. gondii strains are being submitted to NCBI and included here in ToxoDB prior to complete annotation.  Once annotation is complete and submitted to GenBank, the entries for these new genomes will be updated in ToxoDB.  The users of any released data are expected to act responsibly to recognize the scientific contribution of the data producers by following normal standards of scientific etiquette and fair use of unpublished data.  In particular, we ask that users not perform genome wide comparisons/analyses of the sequence/open reading frames/genes of the data sets deposited here without first contacting the organizing committee.  We welcome your input in this process, but would also like to coordinate community efforts to with the goal of producing a collective report for publication.  If you have an idea for analyses that would be useful, please contact one of us to coordinate your contribution to the community effort.</p><br>
<p>Brian Brunk, Hernan Lorenzi, David Roos & David Sibley, on behalf of the Toxoplasma genome consortium, representing the white paper committee, the JCVI genome sequencing center, and the ToxoDB team.</p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Gregory_VEG_mRNA_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned mRNA RNA-Seqs (VEG)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[
         <i>T. gondii</i> VEG  Tachyzoite  mRNA Illumina sequences aligned to the ME49 Genome   
        ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[Transcript expression was assayed in <i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoites.  The experiment was conducted as follows:<br><br>
<i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoites were propagated on Vero cells before being used to infect Human Foreskin Fibroblasts (HFFs). T25 flasks containing confluent monolayers of HFFs were infected with approximately 10E^7 tachyzoites.<br><br>
 Total RNA samples were extracted from multiple sources. <i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoite total RNA was extracted at several times post infection (24hpi for RH; 33hpi for ME49, 44hpi for VEG and 36hpi for Nc1). <br><br>
At several timepoints post-infection (all prior to observable host cell lysis) media was removed, cell monolayers were scraped in 700ul of Qiazol, and RNA was isolated from the cell lysates using the Qiagen miRNEasy mini kit according to manufacturer's instructions.  6 flasks (biological replicates) were collected per strain and per timepoint, and were checked for RNA quality using a BioAnalyzer (Agilent). Biological replicates were pooled and total and polyA+ selected RNA was used to construct strand specific small non-coding or mRNA libraries respectively, that were sequenced on Illumina Hi-Seq 2000 and Genome Analyzer machines.   ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>brian.d.gregory</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>david.s.roos</contactId>
    <contactId>maria.alejandra.diaz-miranda</contactId>
    <contactId>daniel.beiting</contactId>
    <contactId>qi.zheng</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.RNASeqGregoryVEG">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_Gregory_VEG_mRNA_rnaSeq_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Gregory::TgVegRnaSeqTS</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Time point in hours]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[Transcript levels of reads per kilobase of exon model per million mapped reads (RPKM).  Stacked bars indicate unique and non-uniquely mapped sequences.  Non-Unique sequences are plotted to indicate the maximum expression potential of this gene.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rpkm_sense,percentile_sense,rpkm_antisense,percentile_antisense</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">520</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonp89_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> p89 strain genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
<p>Data Usage Policy</p>
<p>NIAID is committed to rapid, pre-publication release of genomic data and recognizes that clinical data and other metadata associated with the genomic data are valuable research resources.  For these reasons, NIAID endorses rapid release of all genome data sets.  To comply with this policy, the whole genome sequences of T. gondii strains are being submitted to NCBI and included here in ToxoDB prior to complete annotation.  Once annotation is complete and submitted to GenBank, the entries for these new genomes will be updated in ToxoDB.  The users of any released data are expected to act responsibly to recognize the scientific contribution of the data producers by following normal standards of scientific etiquette and fair use of unpublished data.  In particular, we ask that users not perform genome wide comparisons/analyses of the sequence/open reading frames/genes of the data sets deposited here without first contacting the organizing committee.  We welcome your input in this process, but would also like to coordinate community efforts to with the goal of producing a collective report for publication.  If you have an idea for analyses that would be useful, please contact one of us to coordinate your contribution to the community effort.</p><br>
<p>Brian Brunk, Hernan Lorenzi, David Roos & David Sibley, on behalf of the Toxoplasma genome consortium, representing the white paper committee, the JCVI genome sequencing center, and the ToxoDB team.</p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="ncanLIV_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence and Annotation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
             
            Chromosome sequences for N.caninum obtained from the Pathogen Sequencing Unit at the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute.
                
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>jonathan.m.wastling</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>22457617</pubmedId>  
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.AnnotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Sanger_BAC_ends_clonedInsertEnds_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned B7 Genomic BAC Ends]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   BAC end genome sequences for <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 B7 generated by the <a href="http://www.sanger.ac.uk/Projects/T_gondii/" TARGET="_blank">The Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute</a>.
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>sanger</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Matrajt_GSE23174_Bz_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[ Mutants and wild-type during bradyzoite differentiation in vitro]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Analysis of seven novel T. gondii insertional mutants that do not undergo normal differentiation to bradyzoites.]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[
            Toxoplasma gondii pathogenesis includes the invasion of host cells by extracellular parasites, replication of intracellular tachyzoites, and differentiation to a latent bradyzoite stage. We present the analysis of seven novel T. gondii insertional mutants that do not undergo normal differentiation to bradyzoites. Microarray quantification of the variation in genome-wide RNA levels for each parasite line and times after induction allowed us to describe states in the normal differentiation process, to analyze mutant lines in the context of these states, and to identify genes that may have roles in initiating the transition from tachyzoite to bradyzoite. Gene expression patterns in wild-type parasites undergoing differentiation suggest a novel extracellular state within the tachyzoite stage. All mutant lines exhibit aberrant regulation of bradyzoite gene expression and notably some of the mutant lines appear to exhibit high proportions of the intracellular tachyzoite state regardless of whether they are intracellular or extracellular. In addition to the genes identified by the insertional mutagenesis screen, mixture model analysis allowed us to identify a small number of genes, in mutants, for which expression patterns could not be accounted for using the three parasite states--genes that may play a mechanistic role in switching from the tachyzoite to bradyzoite stage.  ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>mariana.matrajt</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>21209930</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayMatrajtBrady">
<prop name="graphModule">Matrajt::BzMutant</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">bz_mutant_rma,bz_mutant_percentile,bz_time_series_rma,bz_time_series_percentile,bz_egress_rma,bz_egress_percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">120</prop>
    </templateInjector>

  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="etenHoughton_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p>Adam James Reid, Damer Blake, Thomas Dan Otto, Alejandro Sanchez, Mandy Sanders, Yealing Tay, Paul Dear, Kiew-Lian Wan, Matthew Berriman, Arnab Pain, Fiona Tomley. <i>Sequencing and annotation of the Eimeria tenella genome</i>.</p><br>
<p>Funding: BBSRC, Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute</p><br>
<p>The data were produced by the Parasite Genomics group at the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute to the standard of an Improved Draft.  The Parasite Genomics group and collaborators plan on publishing the completed and annotated draft sequence in a peer-reviewed journal as soon as possible. Permission of the Principal Investigator (Matthew Berriman,mb4@sanger.ac.uk) should be obtained before publishing chromosome- or genome- scale analyses of the sequences or annotations. </p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>adam.reid</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.AnnotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_chipChipExper_Einstein_centromeres_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Centromere Identification]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
Identification <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> centromeres was performed by ChIP-chip using antibodies to Centromeric Histone 3 (CenH3-HA) colocalized with antibodies to H3K9me2.<br>
For further information please contacts Kami Kim (kkim@aecom.yu.edu) or Boris Striepen (striepen@cb.uga.edu).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>kami.kim</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>21321216</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.ChIPChipCentromeres"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_isolates_Sibley_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Isolates (Sibley)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   Toxoplasma isolates and sequences obtained from David Sibley (Contact: L. David Sibley sibley&#64;borcim&#46;wustl&#46;edu).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.sibley</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_SNP_WhitePaper_HTS_SNP_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned SNPs:  White Paper Strains]]></displayName>
  <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Paired end Illumina sequencing was performed on more than 60 isolates spanning the 16 haplogroups identified in the <i>T. gondii</i> resequencing white paper.  This resulted in more than two million SNPs when reads were aligned to the ME49 genome.]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[Paired end Illumina sequencing was performed on more than 60 isolates spanning the 16 haplogroups identified in the <i>T. gondii</i> resequencing white paper.  This resulted in more than two million SNPs when reads were aligned to the ME49 genome.]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.sibley</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</contactId>
    <contactId>david.s.roos</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.IsolatesHTS">
      <prop name="sampleList">ARI B41 B73 BOF BRC_TgH_18001_GUY-DOS BRC_TgH_18002_GUY-KOE BRC_TgH_18003_GUY-MAT BRC_TgH_18009 BRC_TgH_18021 BRC_TgH_20005 BRC_TgH_21016 CAST CASTELLS COUG FOU G662M GAB1-2007-GAL-DOM10 GAB2-2007-GAL-DOM2 GAB3-2007-GAL-DOM2 GAB3-2007-GAL-DOM9 GAB5-2007-GAL-DOM1 GAB5-2007-GAL-DOM6 GT1 GUY-2003-MEL GUY-2004-ABE GUY-2004-JAG1 M7741 MAS p89 PRU RAY RH-88 RH-JSR ROD RUB SOU TgCatBr1 TgCatBr10 TgCatBr15 TgCatBr18 TgCatBr25 TgCatBr26 TgCatBr3 TgCatBr34 TgCatBr44 TgCATBr5 TgCatBr64 TgCatBr72 TgCATBr9 TgCat_PRC2 TgCatPRC3 TgCkBr141 TgCkCr1 TgCkCr10 TgCkGy2 TgCtCo5 TgDogCo17 TgH26044 TgRsCr1 TgShUS28 VAND VEG 
      </prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_gb_GOAssociations_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    override="_GOAssociations_RSRC"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Protein GO Associations]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    <displayCategory>Genomes and Annotation</displayCategory>    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 Gene Ontology  associations produced by Lis Caler's group at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_White_GSE16037_Tz-Bz_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Bradyzoite Differentiation (Single Time-Point)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
Lineage and developmental gene expression: type I GT1, type II Me49, and type III CTGara strains under normal (tachyzoite) and induced (Compound 1 and pH 8.2) conditions. Click <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/query/acc.cgi?acc=GSE16037"> here for link to GEO</a>.
<br>The alkaline condition data set was graciously provided directly by Michael Behnke and Michael White.
          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>michael.w.white</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>18433450</pubmedId>
<!-- needs Graph injector --> <!-- make injector -->
	   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayWhiteTzBz">
	<prop name="graphModule">White::TzBz</prop>
	<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Treatment/Condition]]></prop>
	<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[RMA Value in upper graph or expression percentile value in lower graph.]]></prop>
	<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
	<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">140</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_TIGR_Cosmid_ends_clonedInsertEnds_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genomic Cosmid Ends]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
 <b>Sequence from cosmid ends mapped against <i>T. gondii</i> ME49, VEG and GT1 scaffolds.</b><br>  End-sequence data from cosmid clones were provided by Ian Paulsen at TIGR.  Sequencing was done using T3 and T7 primers represented as TH and TV, respectively, in the sequence IDs.<br>Cosmids with the TOX designation originated from Boris Striepen's laboratory, while those that start with PSB are from David Sibley's group. A detailed description of cosmid libararies from the Sibley lab is available <a href="http://toxomap.wustl.edu/cosmid.html"Target="_blank">here</a>.
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>ian.paulsen</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Tonkin_Phosphoproteome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Calcium dependent tachyzoite phosphoproteome (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Protein samples were prepared from T. gondii RH strain tachyzoites that were stimulated with the calcium-mobilizing agent, ionomycin. Phosphopeptide-enriched and phosphopeptide-depleted fractions were separated by SCX chromotography, enriched by IMAC chromotography, and analyzed by MudPIT. Peptide discovery was performed on mass spec data using the SEQUEST or MASCOT algorithms as indicated. 305 non-redundant Toxoplasma phosphopeptides were identified. 
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>cj.tonkin</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>21980283</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">true</prop>
	</templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonTgCkUg2_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
         
   Whole genome sequence of the natural recombinant <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> strain TgCkUg2 was provided by Irene Lindstrom Bontell and Judith E Smith, Institute of Integrative and Comparative Biology, Clarendon Way, University of Leeds, Leeds, LS2 9JT, UK. 
          
     ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
   Whole genome sequence of the natural recombinant <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> strain TgCkUg2 was provided by Irene Lindstrom Bontell and Judith E Smith, Institute of Integrative and Comparative Biology, Clarendon Way, University of Leeds, Leeds, LS2 9JT, UK. 
          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>irene.lindstrom</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>19457243</pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Einstein_preprocessed_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Tachyzoite membrane and cytosolic fractions (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
          Enriched cytoskeletal and membrane fractions of T. gondii (STRAIN) were analyzed using three different proteomics techniques: 1DE, LC-MS/MS; 2DE, LC-MS/MS; or LC-MS/MS.
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
          
           Enriched cytoskeletal and membrane fractions of T. gondii were separated by 1D-SDS-PAGE or 2D gel electrophoresis. The bands/spots were digested with trypsin. The resulting peptides analyzed by nanoLC-MS/MS on a ThermoFinnigan linear ion trap (LTQ) mass spectrometer. MASCOT was used to search the merged DTA mass spectrometry data file against the appropriate database to obtained unique peptide hits. In order to extend the dynamic range of the membrane fractions, high pH sodium carbonate was used to remove the peripheral membrane proteins. For a few experiments, the remaining cytosolic fractions were also analyzed. A total of 2604 proteins were identified by mass spectrometry in T. gondii to date. The 2604 predicted proteins cluster into 1534 groups of overlapping gene predictions that were identified by 14455 mass spectrometry peptide hits that gave an average 13.2% sequence coverage. 
           Peptides from LC-MS/MS analysis by the <a href="http://toro.aecom.yu.edu/biodefense/"TARGET="_blank">Albert Einstein Biodefense Proteomics Research Center</a>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>andras.fiser</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>19065262</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_NuclearCoding_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Expression - (Nuclear Coding Genes)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
             <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 in situ oligonucleotide Affymetrix probe data.<br><br> Details of this microarray platform are available at : <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/query/acc.cgi?acc=GPL7186">Affymetrix Toxoplasma gondii Custom GeneChip</a><br><br>A detailed explanation of the platform can also be found at: <a href="http://ancillary.toxodb.org/docs/Array-Tutorial.html">Array Tutorial</a>
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
             <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 in situ oligonucleotide Affymetrix probe data.<br><br> Details of this microarray platform are available at : <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/query/acc.cgi?acc=GPL7186">Affymetrix Toxoplasma gondii Custom GeneChip</a><br><br>A detailed explanation of the platform can also be found at: <a href="http://ancillary.toxodb.org/docs/Array-Tutorial.html">Array Tutorial</a>
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.OligonucleotideProbesAffy"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_EST_Watanabe_ESTs_sequences_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Predicted full length transcripts (RH)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
  <i>T. gondii</i> RH EST sequences (J. Watanabe, H. Wakaguri, M. Sasaki, Y. Suzuki, S. Sugano at <a href="http://fullmal.hgc.jp/tg/docs/toxoplasma.html">Institute of Medical Science, University of Tokyo</a>).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>junichi.watanabe</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_White_GSE19092_CellCycle_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Cell Cycle Expression Profiles]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
         Cell cycle expression profiles from Behnke MS, Wootton JC, Lehmann M, Radke JB, Lucas O, Nawas J, Sibley DL, White MW.  
          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>michael.w.white</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>20865045</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayWhiteCellCycle">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_microarrayExpression_White_GSE19092_CellCycle_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">White::CellCycle</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Time point in hours]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[RMA Value in upper graph or expression percentile value in lower graph.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">20</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_sageTag_White3primeSageTags_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[SAGE Tags]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   SAGE tags for <i>T. gondii</i> provided on 2005-04-26, by Aaron Mackey and Michael Behnke, Michael White (Montana State University). Contact: Michael White uvsmw&#64;montana&#46;edu
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>michael.w.white</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>16324218</pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_BoothroydAnderson_Tz-Bz_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Bradyzoite Differentiation (3-day time series)]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
The transcriptomes of in vitro tachyzoites 2 days postinfection, in vitro bradyzoites 4 days postinfection, and in vivo bradyzoites 21 days postinfection were interrogated by microarray
          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.boothroyd</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>22021236</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayBoothroydBrady">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_microarrayExpression_BoothroydAnderson_Tz-Bz_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Boothroyd::TzBz</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Time in days]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[RMA Normalized Values (log base 2 generated with RMAExpress v1.0.3) or expression percentile value.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">100</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_ChIP_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - ChIP]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_MurrayRoos_preprocessed_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Tachyzoite conoid proteome (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
T gondii (RH strain) tachyzoites were harvested soon after emerging from host cells. Conoid-enriched and conoid-depleted fractions were prepared from extracted parasite ghosts and analyzed by MudPIT.             
          
          ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.murray</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>david.s.roos</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>16518471</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonRUB_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> RUB strain genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the  <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
<p>Data Usage Policy</p>
<p>NIAID is committed to rapid, pre-publication release of genomic data and recognizes that clinical data and other metadata associated with the genomic data are valuable research resources.  For these reasons, NIAID endorses rapid release of all genome data sets.  To comply with this policy, the whole genome sequences of T. gondii strains are being submitted to NCBI and included here in ToxoDB prior to complete annotation.  Once annotation is complete and submitted to GenBank, the entries for these new genomes will be updated in ToxoDB.  The users of any released data are expected to act responsibly to recognize the scientific contribution of the data producers by following normal standards of scientific etiquette and fair use of unpublished data.  In particular, we ask that users not perform genome wide comparisons/analyses of the sequence/open reading frames/genes of the data sets deposited here without first contacting the organizing committee.  We welcome your input in this process, but would also like to coordinate community efforts to with the goal of producing a collective report for publication.  If you have an idea for analyses that would be useful, please contact one of us to coordinate your contribution to the community effort.</p><br>
<p>Brian Brunk, Hernan Lorenzi, David Roos & David Sibley, on behalf of the Toxoplasma genome consortium, representing the white paper committee, the JCVI genome sequencing center, and the ToxoDB team.</p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonRH_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   Scaffold genome sequence for <i>T. gondii</i> type I RH strain provided on 2006-09-25, by Matt Berriman (The Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute), Jim Ajioka (University of Cambridge). Contact: Matt Berriman mb4&#64;sanger&#46;ac&#46;uk. (Chromosomes Ia and Ib only).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>matthew.berriman</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.AnnotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonGT1_insertScaffoldGapFeatures_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Scaffold Gaps]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Scaffold Gaps]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
       Gaps within chromosomes represented as features.
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>jcvi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_SNP_Amit_nucmer_gff_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned SNPs: GT1, VEG and RH]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            SNPs generated by alignment with nucmer of GT1, VEG and RH resequencing to reference. Contact: David Roos for further information.         
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.SNPs"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_chipChipExper_Hakimi.Ali.2_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Chromatin Immunoprecipitation Microarray - Chromosome-wide binding sites]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
             
ChIP-on-Chip identification of chromosome-wide binding sites of Toxoplasma TBP1, TBP2, RNA polymerase (Rpb9 subunit) and 
the lysine methyltransferase TgSET8 (<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17562855?dopt=Abstract">Sautel et al. 2007</a>). These data were graciously provided to ToxoDB pre-publication. 
 Contact <a href="mailto:Mohamed-Ali.Hakimi@ujf-grenoble.fr">Mohamed-Ali Hakimi</a>, for further information.
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>mohamed-ali.hakimi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.ChIPChip"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="gnipUNK1_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Gregarina niphandrodes</i> genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the  <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
<p>Data Usage Policy</p>
<p>NIAID is committed to rapid, pre-publication release of genomic data and recognizes that clinical data and other metadata associated with the genomic data are valuable research resources.  For these reasons, NIAID endorses rapid release of all genome data sets.  To comply with this policy, the whole genome sequences of T. gondii strains are being submitted to NCBI and included here in ToxoDB prior to complete annotation.  Once annotation is complete and submitted to GenBank, the entries for these new genomes will be updated in ToxoDB.  The users of any released data are expected to act responsibly to recognize the scientific contribution of the data producers by following normal standards of scientific etiquette and fair use of unpublished data.  In particular, we ask that users not perform genome wide comparisons/analyses of the sequence/open reading frames/genes of the data sets deposited here without first contacting the organizing committee.  We welcome your input in this process, but would also like to coordinate community efforts to with the goal of producing a collective report for publication.  If you have an idea for analyses that would be useful, please contact one of us to coordinate your contribution to the community effort.</p><br>
<p>Brian Brunk, Hernan Lorenzi, David Roos & David Sibley, on behalf of the Toxoplasma genome consortium, representing the white paper committee, the JCVI genome sequencing center, and the ToxoDB team.</p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonMAS_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<p><i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> MAS strain genome sequence data were produced by JCVI as part of the <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/toxoplasmagondiigscidproject/home">Toxoplasma white paper</a>.</p><br>
<p>Data Usage Policy</p>
<p>NIAID is committed to rapid, pre-publication release of genomic data and recognizes that clinical data and other metadata associated with the genomic data are valuable research resources.  For these reasons, NIAID endorses rapid release of all genome data sets.  To comply with this policy, the whole genome sequences of T. gondii strains are being submitted to NCBI and included here in ToxoDB prior to complete annotation.  Once annotation is complete and submitted to GenBank, the entries for these new genomes will be updated in ToxoDB.  The users of any released data are expected to act responsibly to recognize the scientific contribution of the data producers by following normal standards of scientific etiquette and fair use of unpublished data.  In particular, we ask that users not perform genome wide comparisons/analyses of the sequence/open reading frames/genes of the data sets deposited here without first contacting the organizing committee.  We welcome your input in this process, but would also like to coordinate community efforts to with the goal of producing a collective report for publication.  If you have an idea for analyses that would be useful, please contact one of us to coordinate your contribution to the community effort.</p><br>
<p>Brian Brunk, Hernan Lorenzi, David Roos & David Sibley, on behalf of the Toxoplasma genome consortium, representing the white paper committee, the JCVI genome sequencing center, and the ToxoDB team.</p>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.UnannotatedGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonVEG_gb_GOAssociations_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    override="_GOAssociations_RSRC"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Protein GO Associations]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    <displayCategory>Genomes and Annotation</displayCategory>    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
  <i>T. gondii</i> VEG Gene Ontology  associations produced by Lis Caler's group at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Carruthers_preprocessed_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Tachyzoite secretome (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
          The excreted/secreted antigen fraction was prepared from freshly egressed T. gondii strain 2F tachyzoites.Protein preparations were analyzed by 2DE-MS or by MudPIT analysis. 
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
          
          Two-dimensional electrophoresis/mass spectrometry and liquid chromatography/electrospray ionization-tandem mass spectrometry (MudPIT, shotgun proteomics) were utilized to analyze freely released proteins from <i>T. gondii</i> RH strain tachyzoites (RH clone 2F used in this study is a  <i>lac</i>Z-expressing clone).
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>vern.b.carruthers</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>bjorn.f.c.kafsack</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>16002397</pubmedId>
	<templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_massSpec_Sullivan_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[<b>Intra- and Extracellular Tachyzoite Lysine-Acetylomes (RH)</b>]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
           MS/MS analysis of peptides affinity purified from parasite lysate using an anti-acetyl-lysine antibody. 
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
          This dataset represents the lysine acetylome for Toxoplasma gondii RH intracellular and extracellular tachyzoites. 
          Lysine-acetylated proteins were affinity purified from tachyzoites harvested from human foreskin fibroblasts (intracellular) 
          and from tachyzoites harvested 1-2 hours post-egress (extracellular). Peptide samples were analyzed by 
          LC-MS/MS and the resulting MS spectra were evaluated with SEQUEST 3G and Sorcerer 2.
         ]]></description>
    <usage>EuPathDB maps proteomics peptides to the genome and provides a search that returns genes based on these mappings. 
    Peptide mappings are tabulated on gene record pages and peptides can be displayed in context with the genome using GBrowse. 
    	</usage>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>william.sullivan</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>22544907</pubmedId>
    <pubmedId>23403842</pubmedId>
	<templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.ProteinExpressionMassSpec">
	  <prop name="species">T. gondii</prop>
      <prop name="optionalOrganismAbbrev"></prop>
      <prop name="isPhosphoProteomics">false</prop>
	</templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_chipChipExper_Hakimi.Ali_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Chromatin Immunoprecipitation Microarray - DNA bound Histone Acetylation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
Using chromatin immunoprecipitation and microarray hybridization (Nimblegen arrays), we analyzed the patterns of DNA-bound Histone H4(K5-K8-K12-K16) acetylation after 4 hours treatment of RH strain with DMSO (control) or 40 nM of FR235222 (named previously drug A) which is a Toxoplasma-specific HDAC inhibitor. ChIP-on-chip isolated DNA samples (input and immunopurified DNA) were arrayed on custom synthetic oligo arrays (387,000 features per array, 46-50 mer oligos, 2 arrays for the whole genome; Nimblegen). Peak calls were made by the data provider.  
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>mohamed-ali.hakimi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.ChIPChip"/>
  </datasetPresenter>




  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_Resequencing_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Resequencing]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>

<!-- 
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_isolates_genbank_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[T. gondii and N. caninum isolates from Genbank]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
<i>Toxoplasma gondii</i> and <i>Neospora caninum</i> isolate data was obtained from Genbank.  
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>genbank</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
-->


  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_primary_genome_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Genome Sequence and Annotation]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
            Toxoplasma gondii ME49 sequence and annotation from Lis Caler at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href="http://msc.jcvi.org/t_gondii/index.shtml"Target="_blank">JCVI</a>).


    
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lis.caler</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.AnnotatedGenomeCentromereWithNonNuclear"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Boothroyd_LifeCycle_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Expression Profiling of oocyst, tachyzoite, and bradyzoite development in strain M4]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
         
Transcriptome analysis of oocyst,tachyzoite and bradyzoite development in the type II strain M4.
<br/><br/>

There were three primary objectives to the overall experiment. 
<br/><br/>

&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
I. Describe the transcriptome of the oocyst through its development beginning with the freshly excreted, unsporulated oocyst at "Day 0" to a fully sporulated and mature oocyst at "Day 10" and including a mid-sporulation time-point at "Day 4". 
<br/>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
II. Compare the transcriptomes of in vitro (4 and 8 days post infection (dpi)) vs. in vivo (21 dpi) derived bradyzoites. 
<br/>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
III. Compare expression data from three life stages (oocyst, bradyzoite and tachyzoite) from the same parasite isolate, M4. This isolate has been characterized as a Type II strain. 

<br/><br/>

The RNA was derived from parasites donated by the Moredun Research Intstitute, Edinburgh, Scotland, UK and belong to the same original isolate (T. gondii M4: J. Gutierrez et al. Veterinary Parasitology 172 (2010) 8-15.)


<br/><br/>

More specifically, RNA samples were obtained from: 
<br/><br/>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
1. Oocysts harvested from kitten feces and purified for RNA extraction at Day 0, (not sporulated), Day 4 post-induction of sporulation (mid-sporulation) and Day 10 post-induction of sporulation. Oocysts were collected and combined from two kittens that were infected with the same starting material (mouse brains containing bradyzoite cysts). Duplicate samples were obtained from feces collected and purified on separate days. 
<br/>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
2. Bradyzoite cysts harvested from the brains of mice that were infected with oocysts (obtained from the oocysts harvested from kittens as described for the oocyst RNA). Mice were treated with 0.44 ug/ml sulfadiazine in their water days 11-21 pi to enable a chronic infection state. Mice were sacrificed on day 21 for cyst purification. 
<br/>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
3. In vitro 4 and 8 dpi bradyzoite and 2 dpi tachyzoite samples are from separately infected cultures of human foreskin fibroblasts (HFF) (replicate flasks for each condition and time-point were infected on the same day). Samples were harvested independently and kept separate for all the subsequent processing and labeling steps. 
Bradyzoite differentiation was induced by growth under low serum (1%) high pH (8.0) conditions without supplemented CO2 as described (Fux, B. et. al. Infect Immun 75:2580-90, 2007).
<br/><br/>
Authors: Heather Fritz*, Kerry R. Buchholz*, Patricia Conrad, and John C. Boothoryd. (* these authors contributed equally.)


          
     ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.boothroyd</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.MicroarrayBoothroydM4">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_microarrayExpression_Boothroyd_LifeCycle_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Boothroyd::TgME49M4</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[1. Time post infection or sporulation (i.e. 4d vs 8d Bradyzoites and 4d vs 10d sporulated oocyst). <br/>2. Developmental form (Oocyst, Tachyzoite, Bradyzoite). <br/> 3. Bradyzoite samples - obtained <i>in vitro</i> vs. <i>in vivo</i>]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[The RMA values in log2 scale.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">60</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_SNP_Gubbels_RH_HTS_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned SNPs: RH Strain]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
100 bp paired end sequencing reads from <i>T. gondii</i> RH strain were generated on the Illumina platform and by Marc-Jan Gubbels.  Reads were aligned to both the ME49 and GT1 genomes using BWA.  SNPs were called using VarScan.
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>marc-jan.gubbels</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.IsolatesHTS">
      <prop name="sampleList">RH</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_estSNPs_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Genotyping-estSNPs]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.SNPs"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_insertScaffoldGapFeatures_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>TODO</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="ncanLIV_Reid_tachy_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Tachyzoite RNA-Seqs]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
      
Transcriptome analysis of T. gondii VEG and N. caninum Liverpool tachyzoites using RNAseq RNA sequencing data.
        
       ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
      
Transcriptome analysis of T. gondii VEG and N. caninum Liverpool tachyzoites using RNAseq RNA sequencing data.
        
       ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>adam.reid</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>22457617</pubmedId>
<!-- needs injector --> <!-- group priority = 750 -->
   <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.RNASeqReidNcDay3">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_Reid_tachy_rnaSeq_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Reid::NcRnaSeq</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[N. caninum Liverpool Day 3 and Day4 Tachyzoite Form]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[Transcript levels of fragments per kilobase of exon model per million mapped reads (FPKM).  Stacked bars indicate unique and non-uniquely mapped sequences.  Non-Unique sequences are plotted to indicate the maximum expression potential of this gene.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">fpkm,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">620</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_sageTag_White3primeSageTags_frequencies_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[SAGE Tag Frequencies]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            
   SAGE tag frequencies for <i>T. gondii</i> provided on 2005-04-26, by Aaron Mackey and Michael Behnke, Michael White (Montana State University). Contact: Michael White <tt>uvsmw&#64;montana&#46;edu</tt>
          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>michael.w.white</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId>16324218</pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.SAGETags"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_ExonIb_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Expression-ExonIb]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_microarrayPlatform_Affy-Amit_Markers_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Affymetrix Probes - Genotyping-Markers]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data.          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
            Affymetrix probe data. Contact David Roos for further information.
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.s.roos</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>amit.bahl</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Boothroyd_oocyst_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Aligned mRNA Seq Oocyst M4 Strain]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
                    <i>T. gondii</i> M4 Oocyst  mRNA Illumina sequences aligned to the ME49 Genome.    
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
For this experiment, total RNA from Oocyst at several timepoints post-sporulation (0 Days, 4 Days and 10 Days) was kindly provided by the Boothroyd/Conrad labs. PolyA+ selected RNA was used to construct strand specific mRNA libraries that were sequenced on a Illumina Hi-Seq 2000 machine. Sequencing reads have a length of 50nt.          
         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>john.boothroyd</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>heather.fritz</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.RNASeqBoothroydOocyst">
<!-- dataset=tgonME49_Boothroyd_oocyst_rnaSeq_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Boothroyd::TgM4RnaSeqOocystTS</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Time point in days]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[Transcript levels of reads per kilobase of exon model per million mapped reads (RPKM).  Stacked bars indicate unique and non-uniquely mapped sequences.  Non-Unique sequences are plotted to indicate the maximum expression potential of this gene.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rpkm_sense,percentile_sense,rpkm_antisense,percentile_antisense</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">560</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Sibley_ME49_bradyzoite_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Bradyzoite mRNA RNAseq]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
<i>T. gondii ME49</i> bradyzoite mRNA Illumina sequences aligned to the ME49 Genome          ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[ 
For this experiment, total RNA from Bradyzoite was kindly provided by the Sibley lab. PolyA+ selected RNA was used to construct a strand specific mRNA library that was sequenced on a Illumina Hi-Seq 2000 machine. Sequencing reads have a length of 50nt.<br>         ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>david.sibley</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.RNASeqSibleyBrady">
<prop name="graphModule">Sibley::TgME49Bradyzoite</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rma,percentile</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">540</prop>
    </templateInjector>

  </datasetPresenter>

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Gregory_ME49_mRNA_rnaSeq_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Tachyzoite mRNA RNAseq]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
         <i>T. gondii</i> ME49 Tachyzoite  mRNA Illumina sequences aligned to the ME49 Genome   
          
         ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[Transcript expression was assayed in <i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoites.  The experiment was conducted as follows:<br><br>
<i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoites were propagated on Vero cells before being used to infect Human Foreskin Fibroblasts (HFFs). T25 flasks containing co
nfluent monolayers of HFFs were infected with approximately 10E^7 tachyzoites.<br><br>
 Total RNA samples were extracted from multiple sources. <i>T. gondii</i> tachyzoite total RNA was extracted at several times post infection (24hp
i for RH; 33hpi for ME49, 44hpi for VEG and 36hpi for Nc1). <br><br>
At several timepoints post-infection (all prior to observable host cell lysis) media was removed, cell monolayers were scraped in 700ul of Qiazol,
 and RNA was isolated from the cell lysates using the Qiagen miRNEasy mini kit according to manufacturer's instructions.  6 flasks (biological rep
licates) were collected per strain and per timepoint, and were checked for RNA quality using a BioAnalyzer (Agilent). Biological replicates were p
ooled and total and polyA+ selected RNA was used to construct strand specific small non-coding or mRNA libraries respectively, that were sequenced
 on Illumina Hi-Seq 2000 and Genome Analyzer machines.   ]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>brian.d.gregory</primaryContactId>
    <contactId>david.s.roos</contactId>
    <contactId>maria.alejandra.diaz-miranda</contactId>
    <contactId>daniel.beiting</contactId>
    <contactId>qi.zheng</contactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.custom.ToxoDB.RNASeqRoosTachy">

<!-- dataset=tgonME49_Gregory_ME49_mRNA_rnaSeq_RSRC project=ToxoDB --> 
<prop name="graphModule">Gregory::TgME49RnaSeqTS</prop>
<prop name="graphXAxisSamplesDescription"><![CDATA[Time point in hours]]></prop>
<prop name="graphYAxisDescription"><![CDATA[Transcript levels of reads per kilobase of exon model per million mapped reads (RPKM). Stacked bars indicate unique and non-uniquely mapped sequences. Non-Unique sequences are plotted to indicate the maximum expression potential of this gene.]]></prop>
<prop name="graphVisibleParts">rpkm_sense,percentile_sense,rpkm_antisense,percentile_antisense</prop>
<prop name="graphPriorityOrderGrouping">500</prop>
    </templateInjector>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_Lorenzi_CosmidEnds_clonedInsertEnds_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Cosmid Ends and Cloned Insert Ends]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ 
       Sequence from cosmid ends was mapped against <i>T. gondii</i> ME49, VEG and GT1 scaffolds.</b><br> The ME49 cosmid library was constructed in the laboratory of Laura Knoll by Amanda Foltz using the vector ToxoSuperCos derived from the Stratagene vector SuperCos. Information about ToxoSuperCos can be extracted from this <a href="http://toxomap.wustl.edu/cosmid.html">link</a>.  The ends were sequenced at JCVI and provided by Hernan Lorenzi.
         ]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>hernan.a.lorenzi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_apicoplast_chromosome_JCVI_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Apicoplast Chromosome]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ <i>T gondii</i> ME49 Apicoplast Chromosome from JCVI ]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>jcvi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.NonNuclearGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonRH_apicoplast_chromosome_gb_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Apicoplast Chromosome]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ <i>T gondii</i> RH Apicoplast Chromosome from Genbank ]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>genbank</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.NonNuclearGenome"/>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonTgCATBr9_apicoplast_chromosome_JCVI_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Apicoplast Chromosome]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ <i>T gondii</i> CATbr9 Apicoplast Chromosome from JCVI]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>jcvi</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="ncanLIV_dbxref_gene2MetabolicPath_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Metabolic Pathways]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ <i>N. caninum</i> - Metabolic Pathways ]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lamp</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url><![CDATA[http://www.llamp.net/]]></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_dbxref_gene2MetabolicPath_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[Metabolic Pathways]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ <i>T. gondii</i> - Metabolic Pathways ]]></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>lamp</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url><![CDATA[http://www.llamp.net/]]></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>

<!--
  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_MetabolicPath_ECAssociations_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB"
                    >
    <displayName><![CDATA[ <i>T. gondii</i> ME49- Metabolic Pathways - EC Associations]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    
    <summary></summary>
    <description></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>TODO</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <pubmedId></pubmedId>
  </datasetPresenter>
-->

  <datasetPresenter name="tgonME49_InsertOldAnnotation_previous_codingSequenceAndAnnotation_RSRC"
                    projectName="ToxoDB">
    <displayName><![CDATA[Annotation from ToxoDB Release 7.3]]></displayName>
    <shortDisplayName></shortDisplayName>
    <displayCategory>Genomes and Annotation:Old Annotations</displayCategory>
    <summary><![CDATA[Annotation from ToxoDB Release 7.3 has been imported into this release. This was done so that changes in 
     GO and EC assignments, product names and coding sequence could be tracked. ]]></summary>
    <description><![CDATA[Annotation from ToxoDB Release 7.3 has been imported into this release. This was done so that changes in 
     GO and EC assignments, product names and coding sequence could be tracked.]]></description>
    <protocol></protocol>
    <caveat></caveat>
    <acknowledgement></acknowledgement>
    <releasePolicy></releasePolicy>
    <primaryContactId>eupathdb</primaryContactId>
    <link>
      <text></text>
      <url></url>
    </link>
    <templateInjector className="org.apidb.apicommon.model.datasetInjector.PreviousVersionAnnotations"/>
  </datasetPresenter>

<!-- Attribution neeeded -->

     <internalDataset name="etenHoughton_dbxref_suspectGenes_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_massSpec_Wastling_ME49_tachyzoites_RSRC"/>

<!-- -->

     <internalDataset name="etenHoughton_contig_GeneDB_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonMAS_contig_JCVI_RSRC"/>

     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_primary_virtual_genome_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonGT1_primary_virtual_genome_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonVEG_primary_virtual_genome_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonVAND_contig_JCVI_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="ncanLIV_contig_gb_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonFOU_contig_JCVI_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_genome_gb_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonRH_genome_gb_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonp89_contig_JCVI_RSRC"/>

     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_dbxref_gene2TwinScanPred_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_dbxref_gene2GlimmerPred_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_dbxref_gene2TIGRScanPred_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="etenHoughton_dbxref_gene2TwinScanPred_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_dbxref_gene2GLEANPred_RSRC"/>

     <internalDataset name="ncanLIV_oldSangerChromosome_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_chipChipExper_Einstein_ME1_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_isolates_ChunleiSu_RFLP_features_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonVEG_oldJCVI_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="ncanLIV_dbxref_goa_from_annotation_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_chipChipPlatform_Hakimi_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_aliasesFromAnnotation_NAFeature_aliases_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_isolates_Sibley_features_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_updateIsolatesInfo_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_virtualSeq_Einstein_centromeres_GFF2_RSRC"/>


     <internalDataset name="tgonVEG_insertScaffoldGapFeatures_RSRC"/>
     <internalDataset name="tgonME49_chipChipPlatform_NimbleGen-Einstein_RSRC"/>

</datasetPresenters>

